Peter Stephen DuPonceau Collection 1781-1844 Mss.B.D92p
American Philosophical Society
- Peter Stephen Du Ponceau Collection
  - ALS to to Stephen S. Du Ponceau, Philadelphia, Washington., 1821 July 10; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    In return for DuPonceau's oration before the APS, sends a copy of his address delivered on the 4th instant to the citizens of Washington.
  - ALS to Peter S. Du Ponceau, Philadelphia, Washington., 1821 July 21; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    Thanks him for address which he delivered before the APS. For copy of address, see 974.8 D92
  - ALS to John Heckwelder, Oct. 8, 1821; DuPonceau, Peter S. (Peter Stephen), 1760-1844
    1p. Questions Zeisberger's use of the term "become" and asks his opinion.
  - ALS to Peter Du Ponceau; Elizabethtown., 1822 May 3; Seckendorff, Baron de
    Bravery of Mr. Ullrich. Desires money DuPonceau offered him for his likeness.
  - ALS to Ebenezer Watson, Albany; Philadelphia., 1823 February 19; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Does not believe the tax statement is correct, contrasted with previous yearly statements.
  - ALS to Ebenezer Watson, Albany; Philadelphia., 1823 April 18; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Questions whether tax statement is correct, contrasted with previous yearly statements.
  - ALS to Mrs. Dolley Madison, Philadelphia., 1824 December 9; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Relative to celebration of the landing of William Penn.
  - ALS to John Davis, Philadelphia., 1825 June 12; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Introduces Dr. Charles Follen who was recommended by General Lafayette.
  - ALS to M. Jullien de Paris, Philadelphia., 1825 September 3; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Writes on behalf of the Athenaeum of Philadelphia. Mentions the APS, Lafayette.
  - ALS to M.A. Jullien de Paris, Paris; Philadelphia., 1826 January 13; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Articles for the Revue Encyclopedique; exposure of the imposter, John D. Hunter.
  - ALS to W.M. Meredith, 1826 March 27; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - ALS to Peter S. Du Ponceau, 1826 May 20 (ca.); Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849
  - ALS to Peter Stephen Du Ponceau, 1824 October 20; Rush, Richard
    U.S. vs. Coolidge. Discussion of DuPonceau's work in the Salem Gazette. Offers three pages of effusive compliments on DuPonceau's work and "calm and philosophical spirit" with which DuPonceau examines the common law.
  - ALS to Peter S. Du Ponceau, ca. 1826?; Hodgson, William B.
    Acknowledges receipt of package of Orientals.
  - ALS to Mrs. Dolley Madison, Philadelphia., 1827 November 3; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Sends a copy of his eulogium on Chief Justice Tilghman.
  - ALS to M. Jullien, Paris, New York., 1828 April 19; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Articles in the Revue Encyclopedique; review of his Delaware grammar.
  - ALS to John Vaughan, Philadelphia., 1829 July 15; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Introducing William Brose, a younger friend of Alexander von Humboldt.
  - ALS to Peter S. Du Ponceau, Quincy., 1829 September 18; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    Encloses papers from W.B. Hodgson for the American Philosophical Society.
  - ALS to M. Jullien., 1831 March 5; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Revue Encyclopedique. Silk culture. Sends work on the language of the Berbers.
  - ALS to General Lafayette, Philadelphia., 1831 May 19; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Sends last four volumes of Sparks' diplomatic collection. Events in U.S. and Europe.
  - Photo of ALS to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, 1 p., 1831 November 19; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Asks him to enclose a package to Petty Vaughan.
  - ALS to H.A.S. Dearborn, Washington, 4 p., 1832 April 2; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Congressional appropriations for roads and canals; land grants; Scioto Co.; manual on the growth and manufacture of silk. With this is a statement of silk goods imported and exported, 1821-1825.
  - ALS to Edward S. Burd, 1833 March 5; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - LS to Peter S. Du Ponceau, Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement., 1833 June 6; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves, marquis de, 1757-1834
    In French. Introducing Dr. Charles Kraitsir.
  - ALS to Trustees of Girard College, Philadelphia, 1 p. and add., 1833 December 18; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Recommends Henry Fiorelli as a sculptor who comes highly recommended by Lafayette.
  - ALS to Isaac Hays, Philadelphia, 1 p. and add., 1833 December 24; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Asks for constittuion and by-laws, in pamphlet form, of Academy of Natural Sciences, to mail to "A Gentleman in the Western Country."
  - LS to Peter S. Du Ponceau, Philadelphia, Pittsburgh, 1 p. and add., 1834 January 13; Maltenberger, M.B, _____ and _____
    Asks for constitution of Pennsylvania Historical Society, for they hope to found such a society in Pittsburgh.
  - ALS to Samuel Breck, Philadelphia, 1 p., 1834 April 4; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Acknowledges copy of Mr. Keating's report. Elections in New York and Virginia. Legal matters.
  - ALScy to James Findley, Philadelphia. Photocopy of original in Charles Roberts Autograph Collection, Haverford College Library., 1835 December 16; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    American Philosophical Society received the geology of Massachusetts. Presented by Whitfield J. Bell, Jr., July 1969.
  - ALS to Peter S. Du Ponceau, Philadelphia, 1 p. and add., 1836 July 30; Coodey, W.S.
    Forwards a book in the Cherokee language, translated by S.A. Worcester and Elias Boudinot.
  - ALS to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, 3 p. and endorsement., 1838 April 9; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Complains that most competent men are too busy to give time to book reviewing.
  - --- to Peter Stephen Du Ponceau, 1839 February 18; Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849
  - LS to Peter Stephen Du Ponceau, Philadelphia, Boston, 2 p. and endorsement, end., 1839 March 14; Prescott, William Hickling, 1796-1859
    Thanks for his work on Indian languages. Refers to John Vaughan and John Pickering.
  - 1840 July 30, Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - --- to Peter Stephen Du Ponceau, 1841 June 9; Davesan, Auguste
  - ALS to J.N. Nicollet, Philadelphia, 1 p. and add., 1842 January 22; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    In French. Notification that he has ben elected to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - ---- to William Popham, 1842 March 4; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - --- to J.W. Francis, 1843 May 22; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - LS to George Ord, Philadelphia, 1844 January 13; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Concerning letter from Roux de Rochelle. M. de Rochelle intends to forward a copy of his poem on Cortes through DuPonceau to William H. Prescott.
  - Abstract of laws of Oleron Philadelphia, 2 p. and endorsement. NS., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Appeals at civil law Philadelphia, 2 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Arguments to prove that the rights of the neutral flag are advantageous to the belligerent nations Philadelphia, 9 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Authority of a factor, 1 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Concerning the calendar, 1 p., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Extract from the Monthly Review for December, 1798 in re intercourse with colonies in time of war Philadelphia, 1 p., n.d.; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Free ships, free goods Philadelphia, 1 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Goods found at sea Philadelphia, 2 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Index to my collection of newspapers inasmuch as concerns neutrality or captures Philadelphia, 3 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - List of books on the law of nations Philadelphia, 3 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - List of books which Mr. Davis is requested to procure from Europe for Peter S. DuPonceau Philadelphia, 2 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Mariners prevented by a vis major from performing their service Philadelphia, 2 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Minor Law of Nations Philadelphia, 1 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Notes on Lampredi, ch. X, Whether enemy's goods are protected by the neutral flag? Philadelphia, 4 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Notes on the case of a mariner dying in the course of a voyage, whether his heirs shall recover his wages and how much Philadelphia, 7 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Notes upon the navigation of neutrals Philadelphia, 1 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Notes upon neutrality Philadelphia, 1 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Of the captain or master Philadelphia, 2 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Of the competent judge of ambassadors in civil and criminal cases Philadelphia, 5 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Of the contract or engagement of mariners Philadelphia, 2 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Of principal and factor Philadelphia, 2 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Receptors of neutral vessels from enemies Philadelphia, 4 pp. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Thoughts on admiralty jurisdiction Philadelphia, 7 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
  - Titles of the Institutes, Digest, and Code respecting the judicial orders or practices of courts Philadelphia, 3 p. and end., Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844